

SYLVESTER ARIKHAN

Full-Stack Developer

A Full-Stack Web Developer with experience in JavaScript MERN stack and building responsive Web and Mobile applications. My background as a Scientist in Chemistry has allowed me to perform quality/assurance, work in a team environment, and put our customers at the forefront of everything. Very interested in learning about Project Management and new technologies. Keeping up team spirit to achieve organizational goals and keep a lasting legacy.

Email: arikhansylvester@gmail.com Address: Schnellerstrasse 101 Berlin

Phone: 01633731957

Link: https://arikhan.herokuapp.com/

Experience

Oct 2022 - Present Software Developer

Consigli AS Oslo/Norway

• Building modern applications using TypeScript, and Reactjs and supporting the company's development and testing processes

Frontend Developer (Part Time) Sep 2022 - Present

FavFap Germany

Feb 2022 - Jul 2022 Software Engineer

Gestalt-Robotics GmbH Berlin/Germany

· Developing, integrating, and testing user interfaces for software in industrial applications.

Tech stack: JavaScript, React.js, SCSS, Storybook, Docker, Websocket, Linux, Git

Apr 2021 - Oct 2021 Junior Developer (Bootcamp)

Career Foundry Berlin/Germany

- · Completed a 941-hour full-stack development training program under the supervision of industry-leading mentors and tutors
- · The project-based program is divided into two parts, Introduction to Front-end development and Full-Stack Immersion
- · Studied and trained through a total of 7 achievements from 60 exercises

- Built the server-side component of a (movies web application). The web application provides users information about different movies, directors, and genres. Users can sign up, update their personal information, and create a list of their favorite movies. http://my-flixdbapp.herokuapp.com/documentation.html
- Using Angular to build the client-side for an application called (myFlix), based on its existing server-side code (REST API and database), with supporting documentation. https://ambabasly.github.io/myFlix-Angular-client/welcome

Junior Developer (Intern)

LocaaTech Lagos/Nigeria

Helped real estate customers buy, rent, or solve daily problems with their property

Jun 2020 - Dec 2021

- Collaborated with senior developers on resolving daily programming task
- Appraised the identified problems on clients' websites and provided solutions using clients' feedback
- Participated and assisted in the testing, maintenance, and upgrade of front and back-end applications

Tech stack: JavaScript, React.js, Angular, SCSS, HTML5, Node.js, MongoDB, postgreSQL, Git

Dec 2014 - Jul 2017

Assistance Quality Control

AKMA Engineering Nigeria Limited Lagos

- Conducted analysis, synthesized, purified, modified, and characterized chemical and biochemical content before and during productions.
- Developed and conducted programs of analysis to ensure quality control of raw materials, chemical intermediates, or final products
- Collected samples and data and analyzed to identify and quantify environmental toxicants through participating in interdisciplinary research
- Developed projects working with chemical engineers, biologists, microbiologists, agronomists, geologists, and other professionals

Education

Feb 2021 - Dec 2022 MBA in (International Business Management)

Ludwigshafen University of Business and Society Ludwigshafen

Thesis: Agile methodology, organizational culture, and service delivery of selected companies in the tech industry.

Feb 2021 - Dec 2022 MBA International Business Management

Ludwigshafen University of Business and Society Ludwigshafen

Thesis: Agile methodology, organizational culture, and service delivery of selected

companies in the tech industry.

Sep 2018 - Feb 2021 Master of Sciences in Groundwater Management

Technische Universität Bergakademie Freiberg

Languages

English Native

German Intermediate

Skills

JavaSrcipt TypeScript React.js Angular
Node.js ReactNative MongoDB SQL
Docker CSS Test Driven Storybook
Development

Certificates & Courses

- Enterprise Resource Planning (Completed training with university certification)
- · Project Management Professional (Completed training with university certification)

Residence permit

• EU Familien angehöriger art 20 rl 2004/38/eg (Gainful Employment Allowed Anywhere Within EU)